Finding Aid for Charlotte Copp papers, 1976-1985
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Charlotte Copp papers 1976-1985 1978-1984
Copp, Charlotte.
0.5 linear feet
88241 Aa 2
Civic activist opposed to tax limitation programs and initiatives and supportive of maintaining existing tax rates and levels of state services. Files detailing her work with such organizations as Citizens Opposed to Slick Tax Schemes, Citizens to Save Our State, Promote Michigan, and Michigan Tax Information Council.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The bulk of the collection came from Charlotte Copp (donor no. 7524 ) in February 1988. Much of the Promote Michigan material was a gift of Denise Dambrowski (donor no. 7145 ).
The collection is open to research.
Charlotte Copp, an activist committed to maintaining tax rates and state services in Michigan, was deeply involved in three political campaigns opposing tax limitation. Her activism stemmed from her involvement in the League of Women Voters and ranged from convening the initial meeting of Citizens Opposed to Slick Tax Schemes in 1978, to serving as treasurer of the Citizens to Save Our State in 1980, to serving on the Promote Michigan Committee in 1984. In addition to organizing opposition to tax limitation efforts, Copp served on the Citizens Advisory Committee to the Michigan Civil Service Commission in 1978. The breadth of Copp's civic involvement is reflected in her continuing involvement with the local and state League of Women Voters.
The Charlotte Copp papers consist of 0.5 linear feet of material arranged according to the ballot campaigns or organizations in which she was involved: Michigan Taxpayers Vote "No" on Proposal C; Citizens Advisory Committee to Civil Service Commission; Citizens Opposed to Slick Tax Schemes; Citizens to Save Our State; Promote Michigan, and Michigan Tax Information Council. The bulk of the material is in the Citizens Opposed to Slick Tax Schemes and Citizens to Save Our State files; this reflects Copp's more active involvement in these two anti-tax limitation campaigns. The materials in the other series are thinner as the campaigns seemed to hold less sense of immediacy for Copp.
The materials consist of agendas, minutes, correspondence, financial reports, background reports, and press releases. They are arrayed alphabetically by type of material within each series. As Copp's most active level of involvement was as treasurer, the financial reports and budgets are illuminating of the widespread support these campaigns enjoyed even during downturns of the state's economic cycle. The minutes and correspondence also shed light on the inner workings of well-funded, well-organized, grass-roots organizations.
Since periodic efforts to pass tax limitations or tax rollbacks arise on the Michigan political scene during the 1970s and 1980s, various individuals, groups, and coalitions rose to oppose what they sensed to be short-sighted fiscal policy. Charlotte Copp was one such individual, but her involvement is reflected in the activity of larger groups. To gain a fuller understanding of Copp's political involvement, one should examine the League of Women Voters collections (containing material detailing Copp's presidency of that organization). To gain a more extensive grasp of the anti-tax limitation efforts of 1984, one should consult the Promote Michigan Committee collection.
Subjects:
Citizens Opposed to Slick Tax Schemes.; Citizens to Save Our State.; Copp, Charlotte.; Michigan Tax Information Council.; Promote Michigan Committee.; Taxation--Michigan.
- Organizational Activities
  - Michigan Taxpayers Vote "No" on Proposal C, 1976 (Box 1)
  - Citizens Advisory Committee to Civil Service Commission, 1978-1979
    - Correspondence, 1978-1979 (Box 1)
    - Sub-Committee Reports and Notes, 1978-1979 (Box 1)
  - Citizens Opposed to Slick Tax Schemes, 1978-1979
    - Agendas and Minutes, 1978 (Box 1)
    - Budgets and Finance, 1978-1979 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence and Memos, 1978-1979 (Box 1)
    - Press Releases, 1978 (Box 1)
  - Citizens to Save Our State, 1978-1985 (primarily 1980)
    - Agendas, Minutes and Treasurers Reports, 1980 (Box 1)
    - Background Reports, 1980 (Box 1)
    - Background Reports, State of Michigan, 1980 (Box 1)
    - Budgets and Finance, 1978-1981 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence and Memos, 1980-1985 (Box 1)
    - Market Opinion Research, Voter Survey, 1981 (Box 1)
    - Organizations (Others) Anti-Tisch Propaganda, 1980 (Box 1)
    - Press Releases, 1980 (Box 1)
    - Speakers Bureau Speeches, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Promote Michigan, 1984
    - Background, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Publications and Press Releases, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Michigan Tax Information Council, 1983-1995
    - Budgetwatch, 1989-1990 (Box 1)
    - Tax talk, 1983-1995 (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous, 1986-1995 (Box 1)